Guide to the Herbert Matter Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 4: Graphic Design Projects, 71.5 linear ft.
  - Subseries4.04: Museums
    - Subsubseries 4.04.02: Guggenheim
      - Catalogs; Brochures; Pamphlets [3 of 3]., Color and b/w booklets and posters: 10x5: 6 3/4x10: 8 1/2x11: 11x17. (Box 170, Folder 3)
      - Maquette; Brancusi, Constantin., Layout with photographs and handwritten annotations. (Othertype 175, Folder 1)
        Unidentified Brancusi maquette.
      - Maquette; Brancusi, Constantin; (alternate layouts) [1 of 2]., b/w layout with photographs and handwritten annotations. (Othertype 175, Folder 2)
      - Maquette; Brancusi, Constantin; (alternate layouts) [2 of 2]., b/w layout with photographs and handwritten annotations. (Othertype 175, Folder 3)
      - Maquette - Modern Sculpture; 1962., b/w layout with photographs and handwritten annotations. (Othertype 175, Folder 4)
        From the Joseph H. Hirschhorn Collection.
      - Sculptures; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 4x5 contact prints. (Box 181, Folder 19)
      - Guggenheim Museum interior; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 4x5 contact print. (Box 181, Folder 20)
      - Catalogs; Brochures; Pamphlets., Color and b/w booklets and posters: 10x5: 6 3/4x10: 8 1/2x11: 11x17. (Box 188)
        Booklets: Klee: 1879-1940 (2 versions), Calder, Abstract Expressionists Imagists, Guggenheim International Award 1960, Guggenheim International Award 1958, Fernarnd Leger, Jan Muller: 1922-1958, Philip Guston, Antoni Tapies, Francis Bacon, Paintings from the Arensberg and Gallatin Collections, Masterpieces of Modern Art. Posters: One Hundred Paintings from the G. David Thompson Collection, Paintings from the Arensberg and Gallatin Collections.
      - Solomon R; Guggenheim Museum. (Othertype 198, Folder 1)
      - Photographs of artwork by Constantin Brancusi; Marc Chagall; Joan Miro; William Baziotes; Paul Cezanne; Albert Gleizes, and others; [Folder 1 of 2].ND, b/w 8x10 prints. (Othertype 429)
      - Photographs of artwork by Constantin Brancusi; Marc Chagall; Joan Miro; William Baziotes; Paul Cezanne; Albert Gleizes, and others; [Folder 2 of 2].ND, b/w 8x10: 9 1/2x12: 11x14 prints. (Othertype 429)
        Brancusi, Constantin; Chagall, Marc; Miro, Joan; Baziotes, William; Cezanne, Paul; Gleizes, Albert
    - Subsubseries 4.04.03: Museum of Fine Arts, Houston
      - Catalogs; Brochures; Pamphlets., Color and b/w booklets and posters: 6x6 1/2: 10x5: 8x10: 8 1/2x11. (Othertype 189)
        Accesories and Proposals, Newsletter Summer 1964, Guide to the Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, Eduardo Chillida, The Museum of Fine Arts Annual Report 1965-1966, Wilson Morris Crain and Anderson, The Southwest: Painting and Sculpture, Six Master Paintings Two Glasses One Sculpture, Derain Before 1915, Land Without Shade, Some Recent Accessions 1961-1963, Alberto Burri, Some Recent Accessions (1962), The Olmec Tradition, museum membership applications, various invitations to museum events.
      - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston. (Othertype 201, Folder 2)
      - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston., Prints: documents: layouts. (Othertype 245)
    - Subsubseries 4.04.04: Metropolitan Museum of Art
      - Catalogs; Brochures; Pamphlets., b/w booklet (Box 170, Folder 4)
        Lithographs by Contemporary American Artists
      - Art from Primitive Art Museum division; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact prints. (Box 181, Folder 8)
        Peruvian ornaments, totem art.
    - Subsubseries 4.04.05: Unidentified Museums
      - Photographs of artwork by William Baziotes, Pablo Picasso, Paul Cezanne, George Seurat, Philip Guston, Charles Cajori, Georges Braque, and others; [Folder 1 of 2].ND, b/w various size prints. (Othertype 429)
      - Photographs of artwork by William Baziotes, Pablo Picasso, Paul Cezanne, George Seurat, Philip Guston, Charles Cajori, Georges Braque, and others; [Folder 2 of 2].ND, b/w various size prints. (Othertype 429)
  - Subseries 4.05: New Haven Railroad
    - New Haven Railroad [1 of 2]. (Othertype 204, Folder 3)
    - New Haven Railroad [2 of 2]. (Othertype 204, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4.06: Boston-Maine Railroad
    - Boston-Maine Railroad [1 of 2]. (Othertype 195, Folder 1)
    - Boston-Maine Railroad [2 of 2]. (Othertype 195, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4.07: Florida National Bank
    - Florida National Bank. (Othertype 196)
    - Florida National Bank.ND, Various cut-outs: tracings: and drawings of logos. (Othertype 418)
  - 4.08: Matter Tea Room
    - Matter Tea Room photographs; postcards; [1 of 3]. (Othertype 206, Folder 1)
    - Matter Tea Room [2 of 3]. (Othertype 206, Folder 2)
    - Matter Tea Room [3 of 3]., plastic shopping bag with from Matter Tea Room with logo (Othertype 206, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4.09: Oxford Paper
    - Oxford Paper., b/w contact prints. (Othertype 144, Folder 6)
    - Oxford Paper. (Othertype 211, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4.10: Zumstag, Abraham
    - Zumstag, Abraham., b/w prints and contact prints (Othertype 202, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4.11: Tishman
    - Tishman Construction. (Othertype 203, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4.12: Container Corporation of America
    - Container Corporation of America; Ink and water; Lumber. (Othertype 199, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4.13: Reinhold Visuals
    - Aids for Art Teaching poster series; Titled prints; color unless otherwise indicated: Spatial Metamorphosis 1958; Container Corporation of America 1959; colored light also appears on Graphis issue featuring Matter; Computer Numbers 1962; Details of Isako Yanaiahara 1960; Giacometti paintings; Indian Dancer: Study in Motion 1948 black and white; Pravina; Study in Motion 1956 colored wire coils; Wyandotte Chemicals Corporation 1962 color refining machinery; Ingenious Packaging 1958 Container Corporation of America; geometric pattern with colored "box"ed., Color 18x24 posters. (Othertype 185)
      Rinehold Book Corporation
  - Subseries 4.14: House and Garden Magazine
    - Contact Prints., b/w prints. (Othertype 140)
      Includes portraits of Jens Risom, Edward Wormley, Raymond Loewy. From 1949 House and Garden issue.
  - Subseries 4.15: Fashion
    - Fashion experiments (Conde Nast 1948) - abstracts., b/w 8x10 contact prints. (Othertype 144, Folder 8)
    - Fashion., b/w 4x5: 8x10 contact prints. (Box 216)
      Vogue
    - Fashion., Color and b/w prints. (Othertype 223)
    - Fashion; Woman in South America 1940s; Vogue covers., b/w prints. Includes experiment with color transparency (Othertype 299)
    - Four model's (three dancing) in park like setting;Fete Champetre' from: The Art and Technique of Color Photography; Simon and Schuster; New York; 1951; Page 150-151., b/w prints. (Othertype 299, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 4.16: New York Studio School
    - New York Studio School [1 of 9]. (Othertype 207, Folder 1)
    - New York Studio School [2 of 9]. (Othertype 207, Folder 2)
    - New York Studio School [3 of 9]. (Othertype 207, Folder 3)
    - New York Studio School [4 of 9]. (Othertype 208, Folder 1)
    - New York Studio School [5 of 9]. (Othertype 208, Folder 2)
    - New York Studio School [6 of 9]. (Othertype 209, Folder 1)
    - New York Studio School [7 of 9]. (Othertype 209, Folder 2)
    - New York Studio School [8 of 9]. (Othertype 210, Folder 1)
    - New York Studio School [9 of 9]. (Othertype 210, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4.17: Other Clients
    - Alcoa (ad) 1956., b/w contact prints. (Othertype 144, Folder 1)
    - DeBeers (NY Ayer)., b/w contact prints. (Othertype 144, Folder 2)
    - Americana Magazine (1947)., b/w contact prints. (Othertype 144, Folder 3)
    - Carlo Picchetti - Fontana Di Rome holiday card., b/w contact prints. (Othertype 144, Folder 4)
    - Wyandotte Chemicals Corp., b/w contact prints. (Othertype 144, Folder 5)
    - Equinox films., b/w contact prints. (Othertype 144, Folder 7)
    - Harper's Bazaar; Rio; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4 contact sheets. (Box 181, Folder 9)
    - Westinghouse; Logo developments on plexiglass., Colored paper cutouts between plexiglass: 8x8. (Othertype 184)
    - Carter on the Arts. (Othertype 192, Folder 1)
    - Cummins Engine Company. (Othertype 192, Folder 2)
    - Westinghouse. (Othertype 192, Folder 3)
    - Rebetez. (Othertype 194, Folder 1)
    - BCCI. (Othertype 194, Folder 2)
    - R; Buckminster Fuller Town Hall Lecture. (Othertype 194, Folder 3)
    - R. Buckminster FullerYes poster. (Othertype 194, Folder 4)
    - Stryker. (Othertype 194, Folder 5)
    - Fontana Di Rome holiday card. (Othertype 194, Folder 5)
    - Design for Learning. (Othertype 194, Folder 6)
    - Landplan. (Othertype 194, Folder 7)
    - Wyandotte. (Othertype 198, Folder 2)
    - Magic Mountain (ski resort). (Othertype 198, Folder 3)
    - 7-UP. (Othertype 199, Folder 1)
    - Catalog of Games 1967. (Othertype 199, Folder 2)
    - Arts and Architecture magazine process material., Includes drawings. (Othertype 199, Folder 4)
    - International Association of Art Critics. (Othertype 199, Folder 5)
    - Fortune Magazine. (Othertype 200, Folder 1)
    - Sears Roebuck. (Othertype 201, Folder 1)
    - Four Seasons. (Othertype 201, Folder 3)
    - The Drifter. (Othertype 201, Folder 4)
      Promotional poster for film by Alex Matter.
    - Moon Over Easthampton. (Othertype 202, Folder 1)
      Promotional graphic for club owned by Alex Matter.
    - Association of Professional Schools in the Arts (APSA). (Othertype 202, Folder 2)
    - Charles Chevillot's Restaurant. (Othertype 203, Folder 1)
    - Rebetez, Robert. (Othertype 203, Folder 3)
    - Associated Council in the Arts (ACA). (Othertype 203, Folder 4)
    - Kimbe Optics. (Othertype 204, Folder 1)
    - Union Carbide Corporation. (Othertype 211, Folder 1)
    - Family gravestones. (Othertype 211, Folder 2)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions. (Othertype 211, Folder 3)
    - Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc. (ConEd) (Othertype 211, Folder 5)
    - MIT Architecture Exhibit. (Othertype 212, Folder 1)
    - Sixpack (Othertype 212, Folder 2)
      Promotional material for film by Alex Matter.
    - Studio Associates. (Othertype 212, Folder 3)
      Herbert Matter's graphic design firm.
    - Dow Chemical Company. (Othertype 212, Folder 4)
    - Dow Chemical Company (Rufus, little boy)., b/w photographic montage (Othertype 212, Folder 5)
    - Black Star; New York photography agency; Various subjects including Jascha Heifetz (muscian); Baby Cohen; landscapes., b/w 810 prints. (Othertype 212, Folder 6)
      Heifetz, Jascha; Black Star
    - Arts and Architecture., Working prints: layout components: tear sheets. (Othertype 231)
      Related to Case Study House (CSH) 8 and 9, Eames and Saarinen.
    - Cummins Engine Company., 2 1/4: 8x10 contact prints b/w. (Othertype 246, Folder 1)
    - Cummins Engine Company., 11x14 prints b/w. (Othertype 246, Folder 2)
    - Cummins Engine Company; Harry Weese architect., Blueprints for design trade show exhibition (Othertype 246, Folder 3)
      Weese, Harry
    - Cummins Engine Company; Trade show exhibition., 8x10 color prints mounted (Othertype 246, Folder 4)
    - Cummins Engine Company; Trade show exhibition description., Documents (Othertype 246, Folder 5)
    - Display studies for MIT.ND, 10 1/2x29 1/2 poster board with black ink and pencil drawing of computer tape enlarged from original source. Original source of computer tape is 7/8x7 with holes. (Othertype 416)
    - Arts and Architecture (oversized).ND, Various cut-outs of hands and head mounted on posterboard. (Othertype 416)
    - Technology Square.ND, Various logos drawn on tracing paper and posterboards. (Othertype 416)
    - Eames, Charles; Molded plywood glider wings and baby.ND, b/w 2 1/4 contact prints. (Othertype 416)
    - Carlo Picchetti's Fontana Di Rome holiday card.ND, b/w 11x14print. (Othertype 416)
  - Subseries 4.18: Unidentified Clients
    - Le Corbusier paintings; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4 contact sheet. (Box 181, Folder 1)
    - Rudolph, Paul; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4 contact sheet. (Box 181, Folder 2)
      Includes typed letter and envelope.
    - Residential interior; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact prints. (Box 181, Folder 3)
    - 17 American Painters Brussels Fair ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact prints. (Box 181, Folder 4)
    - Oscar Nitschke. Aluminum building model; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 120 mm. contact sheets. (Box 181, Folder 5)
      Nitschke, Oscar
    - MIT Architects Collaborative - Gropius; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w print. (Box 181, Folder 6)
    - Portraits of Cassandre; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4 contact sheets. (Box 181, Folder 10)
    - Portraits ofMr; Tamayo; Ruffino Tamayo; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4 contact sheets. (Box 181, Folder 11)
      Tamayo, Ruffino
    - Art - pencil drawings of woman; baby; landscape; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact prints. (Box 181, Folder 12)
    - Portraits of Pierre Matisse; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4 contact sheets. (Box 181, Folder 13)
    - Portraits of Cyril Ritchard (actor); ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4: 8x10 contact sheets. (Box 181, Folder 14)
      From Vogue, November 1, 1956.
    - Printing press; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4 contact sheets. (Box 181, Folder 15)
    - Primitive relief sculpture; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact sheets. (Box 181, Folder 16)
    - Vertical wooden sculpture; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact sheets. (Box 181, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified architectural model; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact sheets. (Box 181, Folder 18)
    - James Johnson Sweeney's apartment; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 8x10 prints. (Box 181, Folder 24)
    - Madame Simone; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4: 8x10 prints. (Box 181, Folder 25)
    - Eames presentation board; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4 contact prints. (Box 181, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified Client work [1 of 2]. (Othertype 193, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified Client work [2 of 2]. (Othertype 193, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified designs; drawings; sketches. (Othertype 204, Folder 5)
    - Montage (3) Cut and paste; Unidentified designs., Require extensive conservation. (Othertype 204, Folder 6)
    - Pepsi NYC building exterior., b/w 2 1/4: 11x17 prints. (Othertype 233, Folder 1)
    - Rockefeller Center stylized at night (mounted)., b/w prints: cut-outs. (Othertype 233, Folder 2)
    - Montage with leaves., b/w prints: cut-outs. (Othertype 233, Folder 3)
    - Rockefeller Center exterior day; Office interior., b/w 2 1/4: 11x17 prints. (Othertype 233, Folder 4)
    - Modern textiles showroom - interior., b/w 2 1/4: 11x17 prints. (Othertype 233, Folder 5)
    - Black cat (studio)., b/w prints: cut-outs. (Othertype 233, Folder 6)
    - Brazil city building exterior with blossoms (mounted)., b/w prints: cut-outs. (Othertype 233, Folder 7)
    - AlexPundy Matter with baseball glove., b/w prints: cut-outs. (Othertype 233, Folder 8)
    - Fashion model on newsprint paper (faded)., b/w prints: cut-outs. (Othertype 233, Folder 9)
    - Color montage layout with nautical theme., b/w prints: cut-outs. (Othertype 233, Folder 10)
    - Circles; spheres drawn in red and blue ink., b/w prints: cut-outs. (Othertype 233, Folder 11)
    - Hamilton Nursery School; 1949., b/w 8x10 prints. Includes contact prints. (Othertype 233, Folder 12)
    - Barnes; Edward Larrabee; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w print. (Othertype 261, Folder 27)
    - Ice cubes; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w 8x10 prints. (Othertype 261, Folder 28)
    - TWA pilot on scale model runway; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w 8x10 prints. (Othertype 261, Folder 29)
    - Water abstract; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact sheet. (Othertype 261, Folder 30)
    - Serpent-warrior artwork; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact sheets. (Othertype 261, Folder 31)
    - Water-glass experiment; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact sheets. (Othertype 261, Folder 32)
    - Skier downhill; Includes skiers; Canada; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w prints and 8x10 contact sheets. (Othertype 261, Folder 33)
    - Abstract with wood; string in studio; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact sheets. (Othertype 261, Folder 34)
    - Baseball glove; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact sheets. (Othertype 261, Folder 35)
    - Sert, Jose Luis; House and Garden January 1952 (Sert House); ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w 4x5 contact prints. (Othertype 261, Folder 36)
    - Mary Callery sculptures; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4 contact prints. (Othertype 261, Folder 37)
      Callery, Mary
    - Military Tanks; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w prints: and 2 1/4 contact prints. (Othertype 261, Folder 38)
    - Round Globe; ["box" 2 of 2]., b/w prints. (Othertype 261, Folder 39)
    - Fashion at Colonial Williamsburg.ND, Contact strips mounted on board. b/w 2 1/4 prints. (Othertype 419, Folder 1)
    - Baby Cohen.ND, Contact strips mounted on board. b/w 2 1/4 prints. (Othertype 419, Folder 2)
    - New York 1939 World's Fair under construction.1939 ca., Contact strips mounted on board. b/w 2 1/4 and 120mm prints. (Othertype 419, Folder 3)
    - Canada; Skiers; [Folder 1 of 2].ND, Contact strips mounted on board. b/w 2 1/4 prints. (Othertype 419, Folder 4)
    - Canada; Skiers; [Folder 2 of 2].ND, Contact strips mounted on board. b/w 2 1/4 prints. (Othertype 419, Folder 5)
    - Mondrian artwork.ND, b/w 2 1/4: 4x5:4x5 1/2: 5 1/2x5 3/4: 8x10: 10x13 1/2 prints: various size prints mounted on damaged board. (Othertype 430)
    - Chrysler hubcab.ND, b/w 8x10print. (Othertype 430)
    - Pepper grinder using multiple exposure.ND, b/w 8x10prints. (Othertype 430)
    - Portraits of Dr. Hubbard's daughter.ND, b/w 2 1/4 contact prints: 8x10prints. (Othertype 430)
    - Wallpaper.ND, b/w 11x14prints: stamped on backPhotograph by Herbert Matter. (Othertype 430)
    - Portraits of children associated with Dr. Hubbard.ND, b/w 8x10 prints. (Othertype 430)
    - Perfume bottles.ND, b/w 11x14 prints. (Othertype 430)
    - Colonial Williamsburg.ND, b/w 11x14 and other size prints: many are infra-red prints. (Othertype 430)
    - Nitschke, Oscar. Aluminum building model.ND, b/w 11x14 prints. (Othertype 430)
    - Stevenson, Adlai;Stevenson for President campaign prints and layouts.ND, b/w 11x14 prints and assorted layouts. (Othertype 430)
    - Le Corbusier paintings.ND, b/w various size prints. (Othertype 430)
    - Prunes in milk and milkdrops.ND, b/w 8x10. (Othertype 430)
    - Fashion model in profile; solarized.ND, b/w 11x14 print. (Othertype 434, Folder 1)
    - Bermuda street scene.ND, b/w 8x10 print. (Othertype 434, Folder 2)
    - Rock crystals.ND, b/w 11x14 print. (Othertype 434, Folder 3)
    - House construction; studio.ND, b/w 2 1/4 contact prints. (Othertype 434, Folder 4)
    - New York 1939 World's Fair at night.ND, b/w 10x12 1/2 print mounted on board. (Othertype 434, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified woman artist at easel.ND, b/w 4x5 prints. (Othertype 434, Folder 6)
    - Ernst and Karin Van Leyden in their studio and home.ND, b/w 2 1/4 contact prints and 4x5 prints. (Othertype 434, Folder 7)
      Van Layden, Ernst; Van Layden, Karin
    - Flat tree leaf; extreme close up.ND, b/w 11x14 prints. (Othertype 434, Folder 8)
    - Jamaica Estates housing.ND, b/w 2 1/4 contact prints mounted on board: stamped on backPhoto Herbert Matter. (Othertype 434, Folder 9)
    - Trees and ferns.ND, b/w 2 1/4 contact print strips. (Othertype 434, Folder 10)
    - Fashion montage; layout with woman's head above blue water.ND, b/w 15x20 mounted board containing various cut-out shapes. (Othertype 434, Folder 11)
    - Nitschke, Oscar; Aluminum building model.ND, 15x19 mounted board containing 10 3/4x13 1/2 color print. (Othertype 434, Folder 12)
    - Colored pencil drawing; photomontage layout for Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc. (ConEd).ND, 4 1/4x5 color pencil drawing mounted on 8x11 board: 9 1/2x9 photomontage mounted on 11 3/4x14 1/2 board. (Othertype 434, Folder 13)
    - Fashion model layout with headless woman shopper on street.ND, b/w 8x10 print mounted on 11x14 board. (Othertype 434, Folder 14)
    - Crushed paper/foil., b/w 8x10 prints: stamped on backPhotograph by Herbert Matter. (Othertype 441, Folder 1)
    - Prunes and raspberries in milk., b/w 8x10 prints: stamped on backPhotograph by Herbert Matter. (Othertype 441, Folder 2)
    - Ovro Preto, Brazil., b/w 8x10: 11x12 3/4 prints: stamped on backPhoto Herbert Matter. (Othertype 441, Folder 3)
    - Gabo, Naum; plexiglass sculpture., b/w 2 1/4 contact prints: 6 1/2x 8 1/4: 8x10: 11x14 prints. (Othertype 441, Folder 4)
    - Portrait of unidentified married blonde-haired woman., b/w 2 1/4 contact prints: 8x10 prints. (Othertype 441, Folder 5)
    - Outdoor sculpture in snow., b/w 2 1/4 contact prints. (Othertype 441, Folder 6)
    - Sert, Jose Louis., b/w 8x10 prints. (Othertype 441, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4.19: Negatives
    - Subsubseries 4.19.01: General
      - Unidentified sculpture; industrial with dome top., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 1)
      - Unidentified sculptures set of five heads., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 2)
      - Sert, Jose Luis and WienerCivic Center architectural model., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 3)
      - William Lescaze architectural model., b/w 8x10 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 4)
      - McGray, Porter; Oscar Niemeyer architectural model., b/w 2 1/4 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 5)
      - Guston, Philip., b/w 35mm: 8x10 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 6)
      - Modern Sculpture book; Flannagan., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 7)
      - Modern Sculpture book; Picasso., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 8)
      - Modern Sculpture book; Gabo, Naum., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 9)
      - American Drawings., b/w 8x10 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 10)
      - Albert Gleizes., b/w 8x10 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 11)
      - Museum of Primitive Art (Division of Metropolitan Museum of Art)., b/w 8x10 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 12)
        Includes Peruvian ornaments, relief sculpture, other art.
        Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.)
      - Sculpture of two figures running set on pedestal., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 13)
      - Noguchi scultpure set in interior., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 14)
      - Sculpture; Woman's head with hair tied back., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 15)
      - Sculpture; Male head Cesar-like., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 16)
      - Stone head woman., b/w 2 1/4 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 17)
      - Headless female torso., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 18)
      - Arp sculpture., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 19)
      - Mary Callery sculptures., b/w 2 1/4 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 20)
      - Sculpture; Full figure female nude., b/w 5x7 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 21)
      - Stone head., b/w 5x7 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 22)
      - Art-Olmec head sculpture., b/w 35 mm negatives: 35 mm transparencies. (Box 141, Folder 23)
      - Art-The battle of the Taro painting and sketch., b/w 8x10 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 24)
      - Nitschke, Oscar; Aluminum building model., Color 4x5 transparencies. b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 25)
      - Hans Hoffman artwork., b/w 2 1/4 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 43)
      - Portraits of Mary Callery, b/w 8x10 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 52)
      - Portraits of James Johnson Sweeney, b/w 35 mm negatives. (Box 141, Folder 53)
      - Arts and Architecture., b/w 4x5 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 54)
      - Mathilde de Cordoba (artwork)., b/w 2 1/4: 4x5: 8x10 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 55)
      - Poster by Whelans, Color 2 1/4 negatives. (Box 141, Folder 56)
      - Morton Feldman; Buckminster Fuller (seminar); Museum facades; Students - art class;Sally Wedding;Nancy - piano; Shelley Brody; Esteban Vicente; Old Whitney building exterior; nude model; student artwork., b/w 4x5: 35 mm: 2 1/4 negatives. (Othertype 142)
        Feldman, Morton; Vincente, Esteban; Fuller, Buckminster
      - Museum of Primitive Art (Division of Metropolitan Museum of Art)., Color 8x10 transparencies. (Othertype 143)